msdsonline.com 2019-07-13

# 

                                        PRIVACY POLICY
Overview
VelocityEHS Holdings Inc. (“VelocityEHS,” “we,” “us,” “our,” or the “Company”) is committed to
protecting the privacy of individuals who visit the Company’s Web sites (“Visitors”), and
individuals who register to use our Services as defined below (“Customers”). We are serious
about protecting your privacy and recognize that you care how information about you is used
and shared. We appreciate your trust that we will do so carefully and sensibly.
This Privacy Statement describes VelocityEHS’s privacy practices in relation to the use of the
Company’s Web sites and the related applications, services, and programs offered by VelocityEHS
(collectively, the “Services”), as well as individuals’ choices regarding use, access and correction
of personal information.
VelocityEHS participates in and has certified its compliance with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield
Framework and the Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework. For more information please see the
"EU-U.S. Privacy Shield and Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield" section below. To learn more about the
Privacy Shield program and to view our certification, please visit the U.S. Department of
Commerce’s Privacy Shield website here.
This Privacy Statement applies to VelocityEHS Holdings Inc and its (wholly owned) subsidiaries
(MSDSonline Inc. (DBA VelocityEHS), VelocityEHS Canada and their respective Services) owned
and operated by VelocityEHS. The Privacy Policy is incorporated into and is a part of the
Company’s Terms of Use and covers the information practices, including how the Company
collects, uses, shares and secures the personal information you provide, of Web sites that link
to this Privacy Statement (collectively referred to as “VelocityEHS’s Web sites” or “the
Company’s Web sites”).
By accessing and using our Sites, you agree that you have read and understand this Privacy
Policy, and that you accept and consent to the privacy practices described in this Privacy
Policy.
    VelocityEHS                                    1                        Privacy Policy

Changes to Privacy Policy
VelocityEHS may update this Privacy Policy to reflect changes to our information practices. If we
make any material changes we will notify you by email (sent to the e-mail address specified in
your account) or by means of a notice on this website prior to the change becoming effective.
We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy
practices.
EU-U.S. Privacy Shield and Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield
VelocityEHS participates in and has certified its compliance with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield
Framework and the Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework. We are committed to subjecting all
personal data received from European Union (EU) member countries and Switzerland,
respectively, in reliance on each Privacy Shield Framework, to the Framework’s applicable
Principles. To learn more about the Privacy Shield program and to view our certification, please
visit the U.S. Department of Commerce’s Privacy Shield website here.
VelocityEHS is responsible for the processing of personal data it receives, under each Privacy
Shield Framework, and subsequently transfers to a third party acting as an agent on its behalf.
The Company complies with the Privacy Shield Principles for all onward transfers of personal
data from the EU and Switzerland, including the onward transfer liability provisions.
With respect to personal data received or transferred pursuant to the Privacy Shield Frameworks,
VelocityEHS is subject to the regulatory enforcement powers of the U.S. Federal Trade
Commission. In certain situations, we may be required to disclose personal data in response to
lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement
requirements.
If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily,
please contact our U.S.-based third-party dispute resolution provider (free of charge) at
https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request.
Under certain conditions, more fully described on the Privacy Shield website
[https://www.privacyshield.gov/article?id=How-to-Submit-a-Complaint], you may be entitled
to invoke binding arbitration when other dispute resolution procedures have been exhausted.
     VelocityEHS                                2                        Privacy Policy

Canada’s Personal Data Protection & Electronic Documents Act
VelocityEHS is subject to, and complies with, the privacy protection standards under Canada’s
Personal data Protection and Electronic Documents Act (“PIPEDA”). The Office of the Privacy
Commissioner of Canada (“OPC”), through its Processing Personal Data Across Borders Guidelines
(“OPC Guidelines”) allows data processors, such as VelocityEHS, to transfer personal data across
borders. Customers are required to transfer personal data to VelocityEHS only for the purposes
for which the information was collected. VelocityEHS uses data transfer agreements to enable
the transfer of information across borders as well as to outline our obligations of providing a
comparable level of protection.
To learn more about the OPC Guidelines, visit:
https://www.priv.gc.ca/media/1992/gl_dab_090127_e.pdf
Third Party Audits, Certifications and Reports
The Company’s privacy and data security compliance program has stringent global information
and security policies and procedures. Our program has been reviewed and certified by various
third parties, both against specific jurisdictions or international standards, some of which include:
    •   CSAE 3416 Type 2 (Canada)
    •   SSAE 16 SOC 2 Type 2 (US)
    •   ISAE 3402 Type 2 (International)
In addition, our internal controls have been externally audited, resulting in a SOC 2 Report. This
report allows customers to understand and feel confident that The Company’s internal controls
that process your data meet the Section 100 Trust Principles:
    •   Security: Our system is protected, both logically and physically, against unauthorized
        access.
    •   Availability: Our system is available to our customers for operation and use.
    •   Processing Integrity: Processing is complete, accurate, timely and authorized.
    •   Confidentiality: Confidential data is protected as agreed upon.
    •   Privacy: Personal data is collected, used, retained and disclosed in conformity with our
        commitment under applicable laws, our contractual agreements and as required by the
        American Institute of Certified Public Accountants (AICPA) and the Canadian Institute of
        Chartered Accountants (CICA).
To learn more about SOC 2 standards, audits and the Trust Principles, please visit:
https://www.aicpa.org/interestareas/frc/assuranceadvisoryservices/pages/asec.aspx
    VelocityEHS                                     3                       Privacy Policy

What Information Do We Collect?
VelocityEHS may collect various types of information from or about you. During the Site(s)
registration process and the Company’s subscriber registration process, you supply us with
basic contact information (such as name, address, telephone number, e-mail address and
company name), as well as billing information. This information is generally entered into fields
in the registration and subscription forms and enables you to take full advantage of the
products and services that we offer. Should you purchase any VelocityEHS subscription or
services on or through the Site(s), the information that you supplied during the registration
process may be used to track details about those purchases. VelocityEHS processes data
imported by our customers and end users in their access and use of VelocityEHS products and
services. This data can often include personal data of our customers, end users or other data
subjects. This information is necessary for VelocityEHS to provide its comprehensive
environmental, health, safety and sustainability software solutions. These solutions may include
one of our software tools, implementation services, secure cloud hosting, on-demand training,
etc. The personal data may include contact information, such as name, home address, office
address, telephone number, email address, social security number, photographs used for ID
badges, etc.
Customers can also use our tools to schedule, manage and track workplace incidents, formal
safety meetings and ensure compliance with state and federal safety regulations and this may
provide VelocityEHS with human resource-related data such as date of birth, age, gender, job
title and work history. Also, customers using our tracking and streamline tools to submit
regulatory reports may provide VelocityEHS with more sensitive information such as medical
records, medical bills and doctors’ notes. Our privacy and data security program are designed to
process and protect our customers’ data in accordance with privacy regulations and in respect to
confidentiality requirements.
The Company may also collect, from you, the following personal information about your
contacts:
     •   [Name and email address], in order to forward a job posting
     •   [Name and email address], in order to refer our products or services
     •   [Email address], in order to share an article, blog post or other content
     •   Through our “import contacts” feature we may collect the [name, email address, phone
         number] of your contacts in order to [provide description of use/purpose of collection
         e.g. to connect you with people you know who also use our service]
When you provide us with personal information about your contacts we will only use this
information for the specific reason for which it is provided.
     VelocityEHS                                   4                        Privacy Policy

If you believe that one of your contacts has provided us with your personal information and you
would like to request that it be removed from our database, please contact us at
Privacy@EHS.com.
VelocityEHS may also retain the content of and metadata regarding any correspondence you
may have with the company or its sales and customer service representatives, regardless of the
mode of communication by which such correspondence was made. This information helps
VelocityEHS to improve its Site(s) and the materials, products and services that we offer on the
Site(s), and to more effectively and efficiently respond to both current and future inquiries.
As is true of most websites, we gather certain information automatically. This information may
include Internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, Internet service provider (ISP),
referring/exit pages, the files viewed on our site (e.g., HTML pages, graphics, etc.), operating
system, date/time stamp, and/or clickstream data to analyze trends in the aggregate and
administer the site.
Cookies & Similar Technologies
VelocityEHS uses “cookies” (small text files stored on your computer) to help track and
customize your access and use of the Site(s). Cookies store and retain information that helps us
recognize you when you return to the Site(s) following a previous visit. Cookies may also store
any login or ID assigned to you by VelocityEHS and the associated password, though this
information is stored in encrypted form. Most popular Internet browser packages allow you
to configure the browser so as not to accept cookies. However, setting your browser to reject
cookies may prevent you from taking full advantage of our Site(s) and the materials, products
and services that the Company makes available on the Site(s).
To learn more about cookies, visit www.allaboutcookies.org.
VelocityEHS uses analytics software such as Google Analytics, to collect other information.
Generally analytics services do not identify individual users. Many analytics services allow you to
opt out of data collection. For example, to learn more about Google Analytics practices and to
opt out, visit www.google.com/settings/ads or by downloading the Google Analytics opt-out
browser add-on at https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout
These analytic services allow us to better understand the functionality of our web sites. This
software may record information such as how often you use the site(s), the events that occur
within the application, aggregated usage, performance data, and where the application was
downloaded from. We do not link the information we store within the analytics software to any
personally identifiable information you submit within the application.
    VelocityEHS                                   5                       Privacy Policy

Web Beacons
VelocityEHS uses Web beacons alone or in conjunction with cookies to compile information
about Customers and Visitors’ usage of the Company’s Web sites and interaction with emails
from the Company. Web beacons are clear electronic images that can recognize certain types of
information on your computer, such as cookies, when you viewed a particular Web site or Service
tied to the Web beacon, and a description of a Web site or Service tied to the Web beacon. For
example, we may place Web beacons in marketing emails that notify the Company when you
click on a link in the email that directs you to one of the Company’s Web sites. The Company uses
Web beacons to operate and improve the Company’s Web sites, Services and email
communications.
Social Media Features
The Company’s Web sites may use social media features, such as the Facebook “like” button
(“Social Media Features”). These features may collect your IP address and which page you are
visiting on the Company’s Web site, and may set a cookie to enable the feature to function
properly. You may be given the option by such Social Media Features to post information about
your activities on the Company’s Web site to a profile page of yours that is provided by a third
party social media network in order to share with others within your network. Social Media
Features are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on the Company’s Web site. Your
interactions with these features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing the
relevant Social Media Features.
Do Not Track
Currently, various browsers — such as Internet Explorer, Firefox, and Safari — offer a “do not
track” or “DNT” option that relies on a technology known as a DNT header, which sends a signal
to Web sites’ visited by the user about the user's browser DNT preference setting. VelocityEHS
does not currently commit to responding to browsers' DNT signals with respect to the Company's
Web sites, in part, because no common industry standard for DNT has been adopted by industry
groups, technology companies or regulators, including no consistent standard of interpreting
user intent. VelocityEHS takes privacy and meaningful choice seriously and will make efforts to
continue to monitor developments around DNT browser technology and the implementation of
a standard.
     VelocityEHS                                   6                      Privacy Policy

Mobile
When you download and use our Services, we automatically collect information on the type of
device you use and the operating system version.
VelocityEHS sends you push notifications from time-to-time in order to update you about any
events or promotions that we may be running. If you no longer wish to receive these types of
communications, you may turn them off at the device level. To ensure you receive proper
notifications, we will need to collect certain information about your device such as operating
system and user identification information. We do not ask for, access or track any location-based
information from your mobile device at any time while downloading or using our Mobile Apps or
Services.
VelocityEHS uses mobile analytics software to allow us to better understand the functionality of
our Mobile Software on your phone. This software may record information such as how often
you use the application, the events that occur within the application, aggregated usage,
performance data, and where the application was downloaded from. We do not link the
information we store within the analytics software to any personally identifiable information you
submit within the mobile application.
How Do We Use the Information That We Collect?
In addition to the uses mentioned or described above, VelocityEHS uses the information that it
collects from or about you to improve the materials, products and services that the Company
makes available on the Site(s), to notify you of changes made to the Site(s) or new products made
available on or through the Site(s), to evaluate your needs and customize Site content delivered
to you according to those needs, to facilitate the processing of any purchases you make through
the Site(s), to send you promotional material from VelocityEHS and some of our affiliates, and
for other lawful business purposes of VelocityEHS. The Company does not share information
collected about you with third parties, except with regard to certain special programs that we
offer in connection with some of our business associates, which may involve special
promotions and/or pricing, and in which you are participating. Should you register as a
participant in one of those programs, VelocityEHS will acknowledge your registration and
notify our applicable business associate of your registration, thereby enabling you to receive the
corresponding program benefits.
    VelocityEHS                                    7                        Privacy Policy

Sharing with Service Providers
We may share your information with third parties who provide services on our behalf to help
with our business activities. These companies are authorized to use your personal information
only as necessary to provide these services to us. These services may include:
       •   Fulfilling orders and delivering packages
       •   Payment processing
       •   Providing customer service
       •   Sending marketing communications
       •   Fulfilling subscription services
       •   Conducting research and analysis
       •   Providing cloud computing infrastructure
It is our policy not to sell lists containing personal information about Site users, registrants or
subscribers. VelocityEHS may provide aggregate statistics about our clients, sales, traffic
patterns, and related site information to reputable third-party vendors, but these statistics will
include no personally identifying information.
In certain situations, VelocityEHS may be required to disclose personal data in response to lawful
requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement
requirements. We may also disclose your personal information as required by law, such as to
comply with a subpoena or other legal process, when we believe in good faith that disclosure is
necessary to protect our rights, protect your safety or the safety of others, investigate fraud, or
respond to a government request.
User Data Supplementation
The Company may receive information about you from other sources, including publicly available
databases or third parties from whom we have purchased data, and combine this data with
information we already have about you. This helps us to update, expand and analyze our records,
identify new customers, and provide products and services that may be of interest to you. If you
provide us personal information about others, or if others give us your information, we will only
use that information for the specific reason for which it was provided to us.
Examples of the types of personal information that may be obtained from public sources or
purchased from third parties and combined with information we already have about you, may
include:
       •   Purchased marketing data about our customers from third parties that is combined with
           information we already have about you, to create more tailored advertising and
           products.
     VelocityEHS                                  8                      Privacy Policy

What Choices Do You Have?
You may update at any time the information about you and your personal preferences that is
stored from your Site or subscriber registration. You may also ask us at any time to correct any
inaccuracies contained in your information or to remove your name from our list of Site users
who wish to receive electronic communications and e-mail advertisements from VelocityEHS
and our affiliates by simply sending such a request to us at the numbers or addresses given
below. Once you opt-out, we will honor your choice until you inform us otherwise.
We partner with a third party to display advertising on our website or to manage our advertising
on other sites. Our third-party partner may use cookies or similar technologies in order to provide
you advertising based upon your browsing activities and interests. If you wish to opt out of
interest-based advertising click here or if located in the European Union click here. Please note
you will continue to receive generic ads.
Access
Upon request, VelocityEHS will provide you with information about whether we hold any of your
personal information. You may access, correct, or request deletion of your personal information
by logging into your account, or contacting us at Privacy@EHS.com.
The Company will respond to your request within a reasonable timeframe.
VelocityEHS may also process data on behalf of our Clients. VelocityEHS has no direct relationship
with the individuals whose personal data it processes. An individual who seeks access, or who
seeks to correct, amend, or delete inaccurate data should direct his query to the Company’s
Client (the data controller). If requested to remove data we will respond within a reasonable
timeframe. We will retain personal data we process on behalf of our Clients for as long as needed
to provide services to our Client. VelocityEHS will retain this personal information as necessary
to comply with our legal obligations, resolve, disputes, and enforce our agreements.
Email and Newsletter Preferences
You may sign-up to receive email or newsletter or other communications from us. If you would
like to discontinue receiving this information, you may update your email preferences by using
the “Unsubscribe” link found in emails we send to you or at your member profile on our website
or by contacting us through one of the methods listed below:
E-mail: Privacy@EHS.com
    VelocityEHS                                  9                        Privacy Policy

By Mail/Phone or Fax:
VelocityEHS
Attn: Data Protection Officer
222 Merchandise Mart Plaza, Suite 1750
Chicago, IL 60654
Customer Service: (888) 362-2007
Facsimile: (312) 881-2001
How Do We Protect Information Collected About You?
VelocityEHS places a high value on protecting information transmitted via our Site(s). For this
reason, we use state-of-the-art security solutions, such as VeriSign’s Site Trust 128 bit SSL
encryption technology to process payments and to provide secure communication methods. In
addition, the Site is protected by a firewall that provides a high level of security. The
Company takes commercially reasonable measures to secure and protect customer-specific
information transmitted via or stored on our Site. However, no security system is impenetrable.
We cannot guarantee that information users supply to us will be totally secure. We may retain
your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you with our
services, comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes and enforce our agreements.
Business Transfers
As VelocityEHS continues to grow and develop its business, its corporate structure might change
or it might merge or otherwise combine with, or substantially all of its assets might be
acquired by, another company. In any such transactions, customer information likely would be
among the transferred business assets.
Linked Sites
For your convenience, hyperlinks may be posted on the Site(s) that link to other Web sites not
under the control of VelocityEHS. We are not responsible for and this Privacy Policy does not
apply to the privacy practices of those sites. We encourage you to seek out and read the
privacy policy of any Web site that you visit. In addition, when you initiate a transaction on
a Web site that our Site(s) links to, even if you reached that site through our Site(s), the
information that you submit to complete that transaction becomes subject to the privacy
practices of the owner of that linked site. You should read their privacy policies to understand
how they use and protect personal information that they collect. VelocityEHS is not
responsible for the privacy or information practices of its suppliers or any third-party Web
sites.
    VelocityEHS                                  10                       Privacy Policy

Who Can You Contact for More Information?
Please direct any other questions regarding our privacy practices or this Privacy Policy to
VelocityEHS at Privacy@EHS.com or by our customer service line at 1-888-362-2007.
Last updated May 15th 2018, VelocityEHS, All rights reserved.
    VelocityEHS                                 11                   Privacy Policy
